Register of the Claire Lee Chennault Papers 1941-1967
Hoover Institution Archives
Claire Lee Chennault papers
1941-1967
67002
Hoover Institution Archives
12 manuscript boxes, 1 card file box, 3 envelopes (5.4 linear feet)
Correspondence, orders, memoranda, reports, and speeches and writings, relating to aerial operations in China during World War II, and to postwar American foreign policy in China.
Chennault, Claire Lee, 1890-1958.
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Biographical Note
1890, Sept. 6 Born, Commerce, Texas
1917 Commissioned First Lieutenant, U.S. Army. Became military aviator
1937 Retired from U.S. Army Air Corps as a Lieutenant Colonel
1937-1941 Adviser to Generalissimo Chiang Kai-shek
1941, Aug.-1942, July Commanding Officer, American Volunteer Group in Chinese Air Force
1942 Commissioned Brigadier General, U.S. Army Air Forces
1942, July-1943, Mar. Commanding General, China Air Task Force
1943 Promoted to Major General
1943, Mar.-1945, Aug. Commanding General, 14th Air Force
1945 Retired from U.S. Army Air Forces
1946-1958 President, Chinese National Reconstruction and Rehabilitation Air Transport, and its successor organizations, Civil Air Transport and China Air Transport
1949 Author, Way of a Fighter
1958, July 27 Died, New Orleans, Louisiana
China. Air Force. American Volunteer Group.; United States. Army Air Forces. Air Force, 14th.; United States. Army Air Forces. China Air Task Force.; United States. Army--Officers.; China--Foreign relations--United States.; China.; United States--Armed Forces.; United States--Foreign relations--China.; United States--Foreign relations.; World War, 1939-1945--Aerial operations.; World War, 1939-1945--China.; World War, 1939-1945.
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1942-1947 (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Correspondence, orders, citations, and financial and flight records, relating to the military career of Claire Chennault, arranged alphabetically by form.
  - Awards. Citations, letters, and memoranda, 1945-1947 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Financial records. Vouchers, pay authorizations, correspondence, and miscellany, 1942-1945 (Folder 2)
  - Flight records. Certifications, and schedules, 1943-1945 (Folder 3)
  - Orders, 1943-1945 (Folder 4)
- CHINA. AIR FORCE. AMERICAN VOLUNTEER GROUP, 1941-1942 (Box 1-7)
  Office file of Claire Chennault as Commanding Officer of the American Volunteer Group, August 1941-July 1942. Correspondence, memoranda, orders, and reports, arranged alphabetically by form.
  - Blueprints, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
  - Charts, n.d. (Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1941-1942 (Folder 8)
    - Burma. Department of Posts and Telegraphs, 1941
    - Burma. Directorate of Civil Aviation, 1941 (Folder 9)
    - Burma. Governor, 1941-1942 (Folder 10)
    - Central Aircraft Manufacturing Company, 1941-1942 (Folder 11-12)
    - Chiang, Mei-ling, 1941-1942 (Folder 13)
    - China. Air Force. American Volunteer Group. Chinese Chief of Staff, 1941-1942 (Folder 14)
    - China. Air Force. American Volunteer Group. Confidential Secretariat, 1941-1942 (Folder 15)
    - China. Air Force. American Volunteer Group. Detachment, Kunming, 1941-1942 (Folder 16)
    - China. Air Force. Commander-in-Chief, 1941-1942 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - China. Air Force. 5th Route Air Force, 1941-1942 (Folder 2)
    - China. Army. War Area Service Corps, 1941-1942 (Folder 3)
    - China. Commission on Aeronautical Affairs, 1941-1942 (Folder 4-5)
    - China. Ministry of Foreign Affairs, 1941-1942 (Folder 6-7)
    - China. National Military Council. President, 1941-1942 (Folder 8)
    - China Defense Supplies, 1941-1942 (Folder 9)
    - France. Armee. Forces Libres de l'Extreme-Orient, 1942 (Folder 10)
    - Great Britain. Army, 1941-1942 (Folder 11)
    - Great Britain. Consulate GeneraI, Kunming, China, 1941 (Folder 12)
    - Great Britain. Military Mission, China, 1942 (Folder 13)
    - Great Britain. Royal Air Force, Burma, 1941-1942 (Folder 14)
    - Great Britain. Royal Air Force, China, 1942 (Folder 15)
    - Great Britain. Royal Air Force, Far East, 1941 (Folder 16)
    - Great Britain. Royal Air Force. Toungoo, Burma Station, 1941 (Folder 17)
    - Imperial Bank of India, 1941 (Folder 18)
    - Thomas Cook and Son, 1941 (Folder 19)
    - Toungoo, Burma. District Superintendent of Police, 1941 (Folder 20)
    - U.S. Army. Forces in the Far East, 1941-1942 (Folder 21)
    - U.S. Consulate, Kunming, China, 1942 (Folder 22)
    - U.S. Consulate, Rangoon, Burma, 1941 (Folder 23)
    - U.S. Consulate General, Calcutta, India, 1941 (Folder 24)
    - U.S. Embassy (China), 1941-1942 (Folder 25)
    - U.S. President. Administrative Assistant, 1941-1942 (Folder 26)
    - Wang, C. C., 1942 (Folder 27)
    - Yunnan, China. Governor, 1941-1942 (Folder 28)
  - Flight logs, 1941-1942 (Folder 29)
  - Memoranda, Numbered, 1941-1942 (Folder 30)
  - Memoranda, Unnumbered, 1941-1942 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Memoranda (1st Pursuit Squadron), 1941-1942 (Folder 2)
  - Orders, Field, 1941-1942 (Folder 3)
  - Orders, General, 1941 (Folder 4)
  - Orders, Movement, 1941 (Folder 5)
  - Orders, Operations, 1941-1942 (Folder 6)
  - Orders, Special, 1941-1942 (Folder 7-9)
  - Orders, Special (1st Pursuit Squadron), 1942 (Folder 10)
  - Reports, Combat, 1942 (Folder 11)
  - Reports, Flight, 1942 (Folder 12)
  - Reports, Operations, 1941-1942 (Folder 13)
  - Rosters, 1941-1942 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Subject file, 1941-1942 (Folder 2)
    - Aerial operations. Correspondence, radiograms, minutes, plans, and memoranda, 1941-1942
    - Air bases. Correspondence, radiograms, memoranda, and lists, 1941-1942 (Folder 3)
    - Air pilots. Lists, and statistics, 1941-1942 (Folder 4)
    - Airplanes (Folder 5)
      - Motors. Correspondence, radiograms, memoranda, and lists, 1941-1942
      - Procurement. Correspondence, radiograms, memoranda, and lists, 1941-1942 (Folder 6)
    - Armaments - Procurement. Correspondence, radiograms, memoranda, lists, and bulletin, 1941-1942 (Folder 7)
    - Battles. Records of victories and losses, 1941-1942 (Folder 8)
    - Bonus payments. Correspondence, radiograms, memoranda, and lists, 1941-1942 (Folder 9)
    - Casualties. Correspondence, memoranda, lists, and radiograms, 1941-1942 (Folder 10)
    - Central Aircraft Manufacturing Company. Legal agreements, notes, memoranda, and radiograms, 1941-1942 (Folder 11)
    - Communications. Correspondence, radiograms, memoranda, and lists, 1941-1942 (Folder 12)
    - Finance. Correspondence, radiograms, memoranda, and financial statements, 1941-1942 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Flight engineering. Correspondence, radiograms, memoranda, and lists, 1941-1942 (Folder 2)
    - Great Britain. Royal Air Force. Correspondence, radiograms, memoranda, notes, and lists, 1941-1942 (Folder 3)
    - Japan. Air Force. Translation of manual, 1941 (Folder 4)
    - Medals, badges, decorations, etc. Correspondence, radiograms, citations, memoranda, lists, and regulations, 1942 (Folder 5)
    - Medical and sanitary affairs (Folder 6-7)
      - Case records, 1941-1942
      - Certificates, 1941-1942 (Folder 8)
      - Correspondence, 1941-1942 (Folder 9)
      - Miscellany. Memoranda, lists, and blue-prints, 1941-1942 (Folder 10)
      - Sick reports, 1941-1942 (Folder 11-12)
    - Medical supplies. Lists, and shipping records, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Military intelligence. Correspondence, radiograms, reports, memoranda, and lists, 1941-1942 (Folder 2)
    - Military supplies - Procurement. Correspondence, radiograms, reports, memoranda, and lists, 1941-1942 (Folder 3-4)
    - Organization. Correspondence, plans, charts, and lists, 1941 (Folder 5)
    - Personnel (Folder 6)
      - Correspondence, 1941-1942
      - Discharge reports, 1941 (Folder 7)
      - Information sheets (1st Pursuit Squadron) (Folder 8-9)
        - Ground personnel, 1941-1942
        - Pilots, 1941-1942 (Folder 10)
      - Miscellany. Legal agreements, lists, notes, and memoranda, 1941-1942 (Folder 11)
      - Status reports, 1941-1942 (Box 7, Folder 1-3)
    - Public relations. Correspondence, radiograms, memoranda, censorship reports, press releases, news dispatches, and printed matter, 1941-1942 (Folder 4)
    - Transportation. Correspondence, radiograms, memoranda, and lists, 1941-1942 (Folder 5)
    - U.S. Military Mission to China. Correspondence, radiograms, memoranda, and lists, 1941-1942 (Folder 6)
  - Summary history, 1942 (Folder 7)
  - War diary, 1941-1942 (Folder 8)
- U.S. ARMY AIR FORCES. CHINA AIR TASK FORCE, 1942-1943 (Box 7-8)
  Office file of Claire Chennault as Commanding General of the China Air Task Force, July 1942-March 1943. Correspondence, and memoranda, arranged alphabetically by form.
  - Correspondence, 1942-1943 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Bank of China, 1943
    - Catholic Mission Medical Service of China, 1942 (Folder 10)
    - Central Aircraft Manufacturing Company, 1942-1943 (Folder 11)
    - China. Air Force. Commander-in-Chief, 1943 (Folder 12)
    - China. Army, 1942 (Folder 13)
    - China. Commission on Aeronautical Affairs, 1942 (Folder 14)
    - China. Ministry of Finance, 1942 (Folder 15)
    - China. Ministry of Foreign Affairs, 1942-1943 (Folder 16)
    - Great Britain. Embassy (China), 1943 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Hopkins, Arthur, 1942 (Folder 2)
    - Noe, James A., 1942 (Folder 3)
    - PM (Magazine), 1942 (Folder 4)
    - Rumen, John N., 1942 (Folder 5)
    - U.S. Army. Forces in the Far East, 1942-1943 (Folder 6)
    - U.S. Army Air Forces. 10th Air Force, 1942-1943 (Folder 7)
    - U.S. Army Air Forces. Air Transport Command, 1943 (Folder 8)
    - U.S. Army Air Forces. China Air Task Force. Communications Officer, 1943 (Folder 9)
    - U.S. Army Air Forces. China Air Task Force. Secretary to the Commanding General, 1942-1943 (Folder 10)
    - U.S. President. Administrative Assistant, 1942 (Folder 11)
    - U.S. War Department, 1942 (Folder 12)
    - Yu-pin, Bishop Paul, 1942 (Folder 13)
  - Subject file, 1942-1943 (Folder 14)
    - Aerial operations. Radiograms, and memoranda, 1942-1943
    - Flying Tigers (Organization of veterans of the American Volunteer Group) Correspondence, radiograms, memoranda, and miscellany, 1942-1943 (Folder 15)
    - Military offenses. Letter, 1943 (Folder 16)
- U.S. ARMY AIR FORCES. 14TH AIR FORCE, 1943-1945 (Box 8-10)
  Office file of Claire Chennault as Commanding General of the 14th Air Force, March 1943-August 1945. Correspondence, memoranda, plans, and reports, arranged alphabetically by form.
  - Correspondence, 1943-1945 (Box 8)
    - All-China Comforting Association, 1943-1945 (Folder 17)
    - Allied Forces. Southeast Asia Command, 1943-1944 (Folder 18)
    - American Broadcasting Company, 1945 (Folder 19)
    - American Church Mission. West China Office, 1945 (Folder 20)
    - Brown, Raymond R., 1943 (Folder 21)
    - China. Air Force. 5th Route Air Force, 1943-1945 (Folder 22)
    - China. Army, 1943-1945 (Folder 23)
    - China. Commission on Aeronautical Affairs, 1943-1945 (Folder 24)
    - China. Ministry of Communications, 1943 (Folder 25)
    - China. Ministry of Finance, 1944-1945 (Folder 26)
    - China. Ministry of Foreign Affairs, 1944 (Folder 27)
    - China. Ministry of Information, 1945 (Folder 28)
    - China. Ministry of Training, 1945 (Folder 29)
    - China. National Military Council, 1943-1945 (Folder 30)
    - France. Consulat, Kunming, China, 1945 (Folder 31)
    - Freemasons. Grand Lodge of Texas, 1945 (Folder 32)
    - Glendale, California. City Clerk, 1944 (Folder 33)
    - Great Britain. Army. Aid Group, Kunming, China, 1945 (Folder 34)
    - Great Britain. Embassy (China), 1944-1945 (Folder 35)
    - Great Britain. Joint Staff Mission, 1943 (Folder 36)
    - Great Britain. Royal Air Force, 1943-1944 (Folder 37)
    - Hughes, Louie, 1944 (Folder 38)
    - India. Viceroy, 1945 (Folder 39)
    - Kunming, China. Catholic Church, 1945 (Folder 40)
    - Lodge, Henry Cabot, Jr., 1943 (Folder 41)
    - Mahony, Edith, 1943 (Folder 42)
    - Noe, James A., 1943-1944 (Folder 43)
    - People's Foreign Relations Association of China, 1945 (Folder 44)
    - U.S. Army. Forces in the Far East, 1943-1945 (Folder 45)
    - U.S. Army Air Forces. 5th Air Force, 1944 (Folder 46)
    - U.S. Army Air Forces. 14th Air Force. Chinese American Composite Wing, 1945 (Folder 47)
    - U.S. Army Air Forces. 14th Air Force. 68th Composite Wing, 1943-1944 (Folder 48)
    - U.S. Army Air Forces. 8th Air Support Command, 1943 (Folder 49)
    - U.S. Army Air Forces. 12th Air Support Command, 1944 (Folder 50)
    - U.S. Army Air Forces. Assistant Chief of Staff, Personnel, 1943-1944 (Folder 51)
    - U.S. Army Air Forces. Assistant Chief of Staff, Plans, 1944 (Folder 52)
    - U.S. Army Air Forces. Commanding General, 1943-1945 (Folder 53)
    - U.S. Consulate, Kunming, China, 1943 (Folder 54)
    - U.S. Department of State, 1944 (Folder 55)
    - U.S. Federal Economic Administration, 1944 (Folder 56)
    - U.S. Joint Intelligence Staff, 1945 (Folder 57)
    - U.S. Navy Department, 1945 (Folder 58)
    - U.S. Observer Mission to Yenan, 1944 (Folder 59)
    - U.S. War Department, 1943-1945 (Folder 60)
    - Vaughan, Guy W., 1943 (Folder 61)
    - Yunnan, China. Governor, 1945 (Folder 62)
  - Subject file, 1943-1945 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Aerial operations. Correspondence, memoranda, plans, maps, and notes, 1943-1945
    - Airlift, Military. Memoranda, lists, and notes, 1943-1945 (Folder 2)
    - China. Air Force. Correspondence, radiograms, memoranda, plans, and lists, 1943-1945 (Folder 3)
    - China. Army. Y-Force. Memoranda, radiograms, and maps, 1943-1944 (Folder 4)
    - Flying Tigers (Organization of veterans of the American Volunteer Group) Correspondence, memoranda, lists, and minutes, 1943-1945 (Folder 5)
    - Logistics. Report, 1945 (Folder 6)
    - Military intelligence. Correspondence, memoranda, reports, and printed matter, 1943-1944 (Folder 7)
    - Military offenses. Correspondence, radiograms, depositions, testimony, and memoranda, 1945 (Folder 8)
    - Military supplies. Correspondence, radiograms, memoranda, plans, and lists, 1943-1944 (Folder 9)
    - Organization. Radiogram, orders, plans, notes, and press release, 1945 (Folder 10)
    - Parachute troops. Radiograms, memoranda, and charts, 1943 (Folder 11)
    - Security classification. Manual, 1943 (Folder 12)
    - Transportation. Correspondence, radiograms, report, memoranda, and map, 1943-1944 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- POSTWAR PERIOD, 1945-1967 (Box 10-12)
  Papers of Claire Chennault after the end of World War II. Correspondence, speeches and writings, memoranda, and printed matter, arranged alphabetically by form.
  - Correspondence, 1948-1951 (Box 10)
    - American Bureau for Medical Aid to China, 1949 (Folder 2)
    - American China Policy Association, 1949 (Folder 3)
    - Bullitt, William C., 1948 (Folder 4)
    - Chen, Che-tang, 1949 (Folder 5)
    - China. Embassy (U.S.), 1949 (Folder 6)
    - China. Inspectorate General of Customs, 1948 (Folder 7)
    - China. President, 1949 (Folder 8)
    - Dickerson, Wayne R., 1949 (Folder 9)
    - Fox, Charles R., 1949 (Folder 10)
    - Harbison, William Albert, 1949 (Folder 11)
    - Harris, Hendon M., 1949 (Folder 12)
    - Heston, L.G., 1949 (Folder 13)
    - Hoover, Herbert, 1949 (Folder 14)
    - Hull, Cordell, 1949 (Folder 15)
    - Johnson, Burton H., 1949 (Folder 16)
    - Kansu, China. Governor, 1949 (Folder 17)
    - Knowland, William F., 1949-1951 (Folder 18)
    - Kwangtung, China. Governor, 1949 (Folder 19)
    - Lippmann, Walter, 1949 (Folder 20)
    - Moy, Ernest K., 1948 (Folder 21)
    - National Agricultural Engineering Corporation, 1948 (Folder 22)
    - Noe, James A., 1949 (Folder 23)
    - North Western Industrial Company, 1948 (Folder 24)
    - Stout, James M., 1949 (Folder 25)
    - U.S. Congress, 1948-1949 (Folder 26)
    - U.S. Department of Defense, 1949 (Folder 27)
    - U.S. Department of State, 1949 (Folder 28)
    - U.S. Department of the Treasury, 1949 (Folder 29)
    - U.S. Economic Cooperation Administration. Mission to China, 1948-1949 (Folder 30)
    - U.S. National Security Council, 1949 (Folder 31)
    - U.S. Vice President, 1949 (Folder 32)
    - Vinson, Fred M., 1949 (Folder 33)
  - Speeches and writings, 1945-1954 (Folder 34)
    - Interview on American Volunteer Group, Typewritten transcript, n.d.
    - Speech on American Volunteer Group, Typescript, n.d. (Folder 35)
    - Speech on atomic warfare, Typescript, n.d. (Folder 36)
    - Miscellaneous speeches, Correspondence, contracts, programs, and notes, 1945-1951. 1945-1951 (Folder 37)
    - Speech, China Friendship Day, New York City, Holograph, typescript, and programs, October 10, 1945. 1945 (Folder 38)
    - Speech on postwar reconstruction of China, New York City, Holograph, and typescript, October 29, 1945. (Folder 39)
    - Speech, Victory Bond rally, Monroe, Louisiana, Typescript, December 8, 1945. (Folder 40)
    - Statement on independence of the Philippine Islands, Typescript, June 22, 1946. (Folder 41)
    - United States Aid to the National Government of China, Typescript, 1948? (Folder 42)
    - United States Can Stamp Out the Threat of War, Washington Daily News, Printed copy, February 2, 1948. (Folder 43)
    - Testimony, Committee on Foreign Affairs, U.S. House of Representatives, Holograph, typescript, mimeographed copy, and correspondence, March 10, 1948. 1948 (Folder 44)
    - Radio broadcast, Army Day, Typescript, April 6, 1948. (Folder 45)
    - Statement, Appropriations Committee, U.S. Senate, Typescript, April 20, 1948. (Folder 46)
    - Statement on China, Typescript, 1949? (Folder 47)
    - Way of a Fighter, Correspondence, reviews, miscellany, and reprint of foreword, 1949. 1949 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Speech, 14th Air Force Day, Canton, China, Typescript, and letter, March 10, 1949. 1949 (Folder 2)
    - Red Cloud over China, America, Printed copy, March 19, 1949. (Folder 3)
    - Testimony, Joint Committee on Foreign Economic Cooperation, U.S. Congress, Mimeographed copy, and correspondence, May 3, 1949. 1949 (Folder 4)
    - Last Call for China, Life, Typescript, printed copy, and correspondence, July 11, 1949. 1949 (Folder 5)
    - Radio interview on China, Typewritten transcript, July 31, 1949. (Folder 6)
    - Holding Communism in the Far East, Typescript, and correspondence, 1950. 1950 (Folder 7)
    - U.S. Anti-Communist Program in Far East, Typescript, 1950? (Folder 8)
    - Interview, Courtroom of the Air (radio program), Typewritten transcript, and letter, September 26, 1950. 1950 (Folder 9)
    - What Should Be Our Policy in Asia Now? America's Town Hall Meeting of the Air (radio program), Typescript, and correspondence, November 21, 1950. 1950 (Folder 10)
    - The Dilemma of the Red Chinese, Typescript, March 13, 1951. (Folder 11)
    - Chennault Urges U.S. to Back Chiang's Forces to Stop Reds, New York Herald Tribune, Printed copy, March 26, 1951. (Folder 12)
    - Chiang's Troops Called Able to Seize Mainland if Provided with U.S. Arms, New York Herald Tribune, Printed copy, March 27, 1951. (Folder 13)
    - Chiang Air Force Well Trained, Eager to Fight, New York Herald Tribune, Printed copy, March 28, 1951. (Folder 14)
    - Chiang's Sailors and Marines Praised for Spirit and Training, New York Herald Tribune, Printed copy, March 29, 1951. (Folder 15)
    - 1,600,000 Anti-Red Guerrillas Reported Active in China Proper, New York Herald Tribune, Printed copy, March 30, 1951. (Folder 16)
    - Chiang Says World Peace Hinges on Total Defeat of Communism, New York Herald Tribune, Printed copy, April 1, 1951. (Folder 17)
    - Statement on removal of General Douglas MacArthur, Mimeographed copy, and letter, April 8, 1951. 1951 (Folder 18)
    - The Korean Dilemma, Typescript, and correspondence, May 21, 1951. 1951 (Folder 19)
    - Statement on proposed invasion of China, Typescript, and correspondence, November 22, 1952. 1952-1953 (Folder 20)
    - The Flying Tigers Can Do It Again, Look, Printed condensation, September 7, 1954. (Folder 21)
  - Subject file, 1945-1967 (Folder 22)
    - China - History - Civil War, Memoranda, and miscellany, 1945-1949. 1949
    - Civil Air Transport, Inc. (Folder 23)
      - Correspondence, 1950-1952
        - General, 1950-1952
        - U.S. Congress, 1950-1952 (Folder 24-25)
      - Miscellany. Statements, resolutions, memoranda, notes, press releases, news dispatches, and printed matter, 1950-1952 (Folder 26)
    - Flying Tigers (Organization of veterans of the American Volunteer Group) (Folder 27)
      - Correspondence, 1945-1959
      - Miscellany. Pamphlets, brochures, bulletin, press releases, notices, and lists, 1945-1967 (Folder 28)
    - Fourteenth Air Force Association (Organization of veterans of the U.S. 14th Air Force) (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence, 1947-1958
      - Miscellany. Bulletins, lists, financial statement, and programs, 1948-1960 (Folder 2)
    - International Volunteer Group (Proposed) Correspondence, 1954 (Folder 3-4)
    - Sentner, David P. Correspondence, 1949 (Folder 5)
    - U.S. - Foreign relations - China. Memoranda, testimony, and printed matter, 1947-1949 (Folder 6)
- DECLASSIFIED RECORDS, 1941-1949 (bulk 1941-1942) (Box 12)
  Formerly security-classified records of the U.S. and British governments. Includes some interfiled unclassified records. Arranged chronologically by date of release by Hoover
  - 2011 July release of records, 1941-1949 (Box 12)
    - U.S. War Department, 1941-1944 (Box-folder 12: 7)
    - U.S. Department of State, 1941-1949 (Box-folder 12: 8)
    - British, 1941-1945 (Box-folder 12: 9)
    - Republic of China, 1941-1948 (Box-folder 12: 10)
    - Miscellany, 1941-1949 (Box-folder 12: 11)
      Includes U.S. Congress, China Defense Supplies, and General Motors Corporation material
- CARD FILE, n.d. (Box 13)
  Personnel cards for members of the American Volunteer Group, arranged alphabetically by form. China. Air Force. American Volunteer Group - Personnel
  - Duty record cards (larger cards) (Box 13)
  - Information data cards (smaller cards) (Box 13)
- PHOTOGRAPHS (Othertype Photo file)
  - Aerial photographs of the Kunming area of China taken by the U.S. 14th Air Force during World War II, August 1943. 3 prints. (Envelope A)
  - Photographs of Claire Chennault depicting him in various locations in China and the United States, circa 1940-1948. 7 prints. (Envelope B)
  - 20 prints of Claire Lee Chennault, alone and with others, 1943-1945 (Envelope C)